Look at this, I am giving the same
prompt 3 times to the same model and
3 times it will give me different
answers
What is the prompt?
Summarize the customer request and
identify what they need
What is the request?
Hi, I was looking at your website
and I think I want to get some of
those Samsung phones for my team
Probably around 3 of them and I saw
they were listed at around 25000
each
But I am not sure if that includes
GST or not
Can you check if there is a bulk
discount or not
I am taking this prompt and passing
it to GPT-4o mini
And I am trying to print the
response as well
Here I am doing it for 3 different
times
So every time if you look at the
output it is going to change at
least some of it
Look at this, the customer is
interested in purchasing
approximately
This is the same in both
But look at this one
So for their team they would like to
confirm
Here for their team which are listed
at around
For their team and wants to confirm
the price
So even if our output intent is the
same
The exact wording will differ a lot
When you are giving the prompt to
the same LLM multiple times
Because LLMs are probabilistic in
nature and that is how they work
But a small mistake like this is
going to break your production code
When you are building multi -level
agents
And I am going to explain exactly
why it will break
And how to fix that in this entire
video
So let's get started
So let's say you are thinking of
building a travel booking agent in
your company
And the user's question is
I want to book a flight from
Rajahmundry to Hyderabad on 7th May
To build this solution you have
built 3 different agents
The first agent will try to fetch
the flight details if it is
available for your specific dates or
not
It will take the prompt from the
user and it will try to return you
something like this
I found a great Indigo flight on
Wednesday morning
It is around 5000 and leaves pretty
early from Hyderabad
At that time this output will be
acting as an input to the next agent
And the next agent is the flight
booking agent
What should the flight booking agent
do?
It needs to go to the Indigo
Airlines
After going there it needs to find
the details from Rajahmundry to
Hyderabad
It needs to fetch the flight details
and give it to the next agent
But if you think from this
information the second agent will be
able to communicate with the website
properly
Because I need to see the flight
number in this
And what is the date?
If it is around 5000 there will be a
lot of flights
Which specific flight I need to
take?
And from where should I departure?
So on the output of this first agent
There are a lot of things that are
dependent such that the next agent
can work properly
If the first agent's output doesn't
work properly
This will break itself right here
And it doesn't even go to the third
agent which is the payment agent
Now how can you make the agents
communicate properly between
multiple agents
Which is called A2A protocol
If you want to communicate reliably
like this
You need a reliable information or
output from every agent right?
So that is what we are going to
learn today
Which is enforcing the output of the
agents using JSON Schema
Now let's assume what if the first
agent returns output like this
Airlines mo indigo, flight number mo
And date mo e, date to departure,
Hyderabad, Bangalore, price,
number of seats left
If such information is there
The second agent can take all of
this information properly
And it can fill in all of your
details
And this can be sent to the third
agent
And your tickets will be booked
Isn't it?
And even second agent will also need
to output in the proper JSON format
Then if this output doesn't change
even if you do multiple LLM calls
Then your complete multi -agent
orchestration will not break even in
the worst case scenarios
So what is our overall learning?
Let's say we have the first agent
This agent will always define the
output in the format of JSON
No matter how many times you execute
this agent
This output should be the same
As shown in the starting
Output should not change or at least
the output format should not change
And this output you will pass it as
an input to the next agent
And this agent consumes that input
Even this will give you the next
output which is in the JSON format
So this is also consistent every
time even when the agent runs
multiple times
And you will pass this agent output
to the third agent
And third agent will also give you
the output in the proper JSON format
No matter how many agents you have
Whether it is sequential or parallel
The only thing is you need to build
a reliable system
Such that the output format from the
agent is always consistent
Because let's say if this first
agent is 90 % consistent
And this second agent is 90 %
consistent
And the third agent is 90 %
So when three agents are built
Even if it is at 90 %
The overall consistency is around 73
% only
But what if the agent 1's
consistency is 99 %
And agent 2 is 99 %
And agent 3 is 99 %
Then the overall system's
consistency would be around 97 %
guys
So it's always important that
whatever the agents that you are
building
They are providing or reproducing
the same kind of results
Or at least in the same kind of
format results
Such that down the line the other
agents will not break
Because of the output from the
previous agent
And in this video we are going to
learn exactly how to do this in the
code
First we are installing all the
packages that we are needed
And we are loading the OpenAI API
And along with that we have fixed
our client
OpenAI client
You can use any kind of open source
models as well guys
I am just using OpenAI because I am
just used to it
That's it
So the first thing is how to enforce
the structured output
But before that let's see how you
can expect the output in the JSON
format
When you are hitting an LLM API
So what are we doing here
We are talking via GPT-4o mini
And what is the system role here
You extract the product info
And always respond in the JSON with
keys
What are the keys in the JSON
Product, price, quantity
And then you are giving a question
I want to buy 3 Samsung Galaxy
phones at 25,000 rupees each
And one important thing that you
need to give here is
Response format equal to
Here the output from the LLM should
be in which format
They are specifying externally
What do we want
It is in the JSON object
So you are forcing the valid output
in the format of JSON
And after that you are just printing
what is the output
Let's try to execute this piece of
code
And see here
So based upon this question
I want to buy 3 Samsung Galaxy
phones at 25,000 rupees each
What is the output
So in a JSON format
We got the product information
Samsung Galaxy phone
Price 25,000
And quantity 3
Now you can ask
Bhalaji, it's done right
Every time we get the output in the
format of JSON
What is the issue now
Think about it
Do you see any issue in this point
right here
So what if
Here when LLM executes again
It provides an output here
Rather than 25,000 as a number
It says 25,000
What if text is given
What will you do then
It is in JSON
But the other agent
Agent 2
Which might be expecting this value
to be 25,000
By writing JSON schema like this
Even though if you are providing the
output as a JSON format
You can change the text in the
values
Based on the LLM output
So you can use JSON object as an
output response
But this is not a full fledged
production level constraint guys
Even if you tell it to be in JSON
format
Sometimes if you execute this
multiple times
The LLM might provide or might make
some mistakes in the values of the
JSON
Maybe it will try to add extra keys
Who knows
So this technique works
But this is not the foolproof
technique
Now you can ask
Bhalaji then how can we create a
foolproof technique
Yes
That is where we have the proper
JSON schema
Defined in the response format
What did we do earlier
In response format
We just specified that we want JSON
object
But we are not specifying what
should be in that JSON
We are giving that in the prompt
itself
But it is much better when you
provide the entire schema of the
output that you want
While hitting the API itself
So let me explain what this entire
piece of code in this notebook right
here
What is happening here
So we first wanted this kind of
output
But I want to define the
entire output schema
What am I doing for that
I have the type as the JSON schema
And then we have the JSON schema
And then what is the name of it
We are trying to extract the product
information from the prompt
Strict equal to true or false
And then the schema starts
What kind of schema are we creating
It is in the string format or JSON
format
And what are the properties that we
have in that JSON
What is the property
We have the product name
So what is the product name
And what is the type of that product
name
It is in the string
And then what is the description
No need to get the description
LLM will get more context in
extracting the information from the
prompt
And after that you are saying what
is the price
So the price per quantity
And then what is the type
And then what is the description
And then quantity
Quantity is the type
Description
And here just to show you as an
example
I am engineering one more key
Which is called total amount
We have the price per unit and
quantity
I can calculate the total amount
And this total amount should also be
float or a number
So type is number
And what is the description
Total cost price into quantity
So what does LLM do
By looking at this text
It will understand that by
multiplying these two
I need to create this extra more
information
And then what are the required
fields
Product name, price per unit,
quantity and total amount
And additional parameters are false
I don't want any extra information
So here whatever the output that you
want
You are defining it entirely in the
response format
And when you give this kind of
information to the API
Then the API needs to follow this
output schema
It cannot make any kind of mistakes
So let's go ahead and see what it
will give you
So what are we doing
You are trying to with the GPT-4o
mini again
And after that you put this
What is the prompt for this question
And then I am also putting what is
the response format
That is the total JSON schema
And then here I am going to execute
this piece of code
And see product name Samsung Galaxy
phone
Price per unit 25000, quantity 3,
total amount 75000
So now if you execute the same code
multiple times
You are going to get the same kind
of output
Let me execute it again
And see how many times you execute
This output is not going to change
Because you defined the exact schema
that you want
And the next agent can take this
output
And then it can process whatever the
things
That it wants to process
See this is how you will enforce the
output
From the API using JSON schemas
Now you all have a question
But you used JSON object or JSON
schema
When to use both
So whenever you want to have a
production level
Engineering to be done for the
agents
Always use JSON schema
No, you are doing a prototype
You are doing POC
Then JSON object would be fine
But try to prefer to JSON schema
Now the next part
Which is the important part
Which is called output validation
So let's say I have an agent here
From this agent
You got an output in the format of
JSON
And the output is going to go into
the next agent
And this is going to do its
processing
But even when you enforce
Every single thing in the JSON
schema
It could make mistakes
Or it might make mistakes
Because of some external factors
So if you pass this one
Then this agent will break
And in that situation usually
1 % or 0.5 %
But even to catch that 1 % or 0.5 %
What are we going to do
We are going to add a validation
step
So what is this validation step
The output that we got
Is it in the expected JSON format
Or not
So you will check this validation
And if the validation is true
Then only send this output as an
input
To the next agent
And then you process that
And then you do the validation
And then you give it to the next
agent
So it's always you have the prompt
You get the output from the agent
And that should be in the JSON
schema
And then you also validate
Whether it's a correct JSON schema
or not
And once the validation is done
Send it to the next agent
And repeat the process
What happens when you do this
You are trying to minimize as many
errors as possible
So let's go ahead and see
How you can do the validation part
We need this kind of JSON right
Now how do I validate this JSON
So I can pass that JSON as an input
To this function validate product
response
And first I will try to load it in
the JSON package
If I think it's loading
Then it's a valid JSON
Otherwise return some error
It's not a valid JSON
After loading
Do I have all the keys I need
I am checking if there are any
missing keys
If there are missing keys then don't
send it
If everything is fine then go for
the next check
Whether my data types are not
correct
So data product name is not string
Price per unit is float or integer
Quantity integer is not
So I am looking at all of these
things
And I am doing data validation in
JSON
And here price per unit for my
business use case
It cannot be less than 0
And quantity cannot be less than 0
So I am also checking all of these
things
Such that our output from the LLM
Even though it is in the proper
format
We are just validating
If everything feels right or wrong
Then you pass that output JSON
To this function
And then it will validate
And if it validates then send it to
the next agent
So just to replicate that kind of
flow
I created multiple examples
So what did I do first
I created a valid response
And then I am passing it to the same
function
And it is saying it is good data
And next time I am not putting it as
JSON
And it says bad JSON
Next I am missing some product keys
And I got the missing values
And next I got the bad values
And I got the bad value
So you can do the validation at
every step
And then you send it to the next
agent
Very simple
And the next step is
Combining the structured output
Plus validation and retry
So we did 3 steps
We are putting these 3 steps
In the same information or function
So for every time
If the agent fails
I want to do a max retrace of 3
times
And then here we are doing the LLM
call
We will get the output response
After that you are passing it
To the validator product response
And if it is successful
Then return the result
If it is not successful
Then try the next attempt
If it doesn't work then
cut off
So the flow should be something like
this
You should call the agent
You should pass the output
And you should validate the output
And use it or retry if it doesn't
validate it
That is what a simple agentic loop
is
Many people say this is complex
But nothing complex at all
If you use Lang chain
All of this code will become even
smaller
I am teaching you from scratch
Everything from scratch
Do you understand that
So in this video
You see the need for
Why do we need a structured
Output for every agent output
Because if it doesn't work
Then multiple ends will break in the
down the line
Now if you want to get such a
structured output
You learn how to define JSON objects
And JSON schema
When to use JSON object and when to
use JSON schema
You will see the difference
And then you put every single thing
in a loop
And you execute that
And that is a simple JSON output
structure guys
And if you learned something new
from this video
Please let me know in the comment
section
And if you know someone who likes
this video
Please share it with them